Preliminary Guide to the Gelman Library University Librarian records, 1991-2008 RG0139
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Gelman Library University Librarian records
1991-2008
1994-2008
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Gelman Library. Office of the University Librarian
RG0139
7 Linear Feet
This collection contains the records of the University Librarian for George Washington University. Materials in this collection include budgets, reports, and working files. They range in date from 1991 to 2008, with the bulk of the material dating between 1994 and 1995.
Acquisition Information
Materials were transferred to the University Archives by the University Librarian.
Historical or Biographical Note
The George Washington University's Melvin Gelman Library opened in 1973. Before the Gelman Library (which received its current name in 1980), the University Library was located in Lisner Hall, formerly Lisner Library. When the University moved to Foggy Bottom in 1912 from its location on 15th and H Streets, N.W., the first library was located in the original Lisner Hall, the former St. Rose's School for Orphaned Girls, between 20th and 21st Streets on G Street. Other libraries include the Virginia Campus Library (established n 1990), and the Mount Vernon Campus Eckles Library (under GW control since 1997). Together, these three libraries form the Gelman Library System (GLS).
The Library is headed by a University Librarian, who oversees: the Assistant University Librarian, Administration, Development, and Personnel; Associate University Librarian for Collections and Scholarly Communication; Associate University Librarian for Information Technology; Associate University Librarian for Public Services; Directors of the Mt. Vernon and Virginia Campus libraries, and the Manager of GLS (Gelman Library System) Financial Operations.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include budgets, reports, and working files from the office of the University Librarian. They range in date from 1991 to 2008.
Collection Organization
Organized into two series: Office files and Jack Siggins records [accession 2012.071]
Conditions Governing Access
Series 1 is open for research. Series 2 is closed for 50 years from date of record creation.
Finance; Melvin Gelman Library; Librarians; Washington (D.C.); Gelman Library. Office of the University Librarian; George Washington University. Library; George Washington University
- Office files, 1991-1996 and undated; 1994-1995; RG0139 Series 1; 3 Linear Feet 2 record cartons
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains office files related to the subjects of the staff management group (smg), budget, WRLC, GW Tidewater and Hampton locations, computer information center, university policies, Virginia Campus Library, faculty senate, friends of the libraries group. The records cover the years 1992-96.
  Formerly ACC#666
  - Working file: Staff Management Group, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Working file: External Programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gelman Library: Three year budget planning document, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - WRLC and Southeastern Universities Research Association, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Working file: WRLC Directors, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Working file: Council of Deans, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences: Orientation Attendees, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Working file: Annual Report, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Working file: Budget, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - GWU Tidewater Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hampton Roads and Richmond Campuses, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sample GW pubs, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Computer Information and Resource Center, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Gelman Library Info, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - GW University Policies and Procedures, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - GW campus contacts and initiatives, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    General note
    Alphabetically by last name
  - Subject Specialists, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Equipment, furniture, LAN, consulting-AAC, networks, CAPCON, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Campus Library, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Gelman Background, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Gelman Personnel, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Working file: Faculty Senate, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Working file: OCLC, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Working file: Faculty Library Senate Committee, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Working file: Friends of the Libraries, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Working file: Technology, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Information Technology: Higher education and Healthcare at GWU, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Working file: Campus wide information systems steering committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Working file: Subject Specialists Planners Gelman, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    time and hours
  - Faculty Senate, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Working file: Subject Specialists, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Working file: Academic Affairs VP, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Working file: Credenza Top File, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Academic Computing Advisory Council
  - Working file: Collections budget and development, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Gelman
  - GW Admininistration and business procedures, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    CIRC Strat Plan
  - Working file: Strategic Plan, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Jack Siggins records [accession 2012.071], 1995-2008; Series 2; 4 Linear Feet
  Conditions Governing Access
  The records in series 2 are closed for 50 years from date of record creation.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred by Office of the University Librarian, August 24, 2012 (Accession 2012.071).
  Arrangement
  Original order retained.
  - VII.J. Learning Organization, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - V.H. Korean Library, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - I.B. Committee on Information Technology, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - I.A. Board of Trustees: IT Committee, undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stephen Joel Trachtenberg (SJT) 2007, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - SJT 2006, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - SJT 2005, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - SJT 2004, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - SJT 2003, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - SJT 2002, Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - SJT 2001, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - SJT 2000, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - SJT 1999, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - SJT 1998, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - SJT 1995 - 1997, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - I.E.1 Council of Librarians: Code/ByLaws, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - I.G. Mission Statement, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - I.H. Mt. Vernon Campus Library, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - I.H.1. Roosevelt Papers, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - I.H.2. Les Dames D'Escoffier, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - I.I.1. National Transportation Safety Board, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - I.J. Organization Charts, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - I.N. Strategic Plan, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - I.O. Surveys, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - I.O.1. LibQual, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - II.C. Capital Budget, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - II.H.1. Merit Increases FY2006, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - II.H.1 Merit Increases FY2005, Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - III.A. Access, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - III.A.1. Woodrow Wilson School, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - III.E.1. Library Hours, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - III.G. Security, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - III.D. Emergency Procedures, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - III.N. (Starbucks) Café, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - IV.B.1. Copy Center, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - V.A. Collection Development Specialists, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - V.E. Special Collections, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - V.E.7 Curator of Africana, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - V.F. University Archivist, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - V.G. Faculty Authors, undated; Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - WF: Annual Report Fy 2000, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - WF: Annual Report FY 2001, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - I.B. Annual Report FY 2002, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - I.B. Annual Report FY 2003, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - I.B. Annual Report FY 2005, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - I.B. Annual Report FY 2006, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - I.D. Cabinet, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - I.E. Council of Librarians, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - I.H. Mt. Vernon Campus Library, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - I.I. Virginia Campus Library, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - I.K. Staff Management Group, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - I.L. Staff Association, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - I.M. Statistics, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - I.P. Symposia, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - I.Q.1 UPD Incident Reports, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - I.R. Student Liaison/Advisory Board, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - II.A.5. Budget 2002, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - II.A. 6. Budget 2003, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - II.A.7 Budget 2004, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - II.A.8 Budget 2005, Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - II.B. 3-Year Planning, undated; Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 21)